Hello everyone and welcome
to EnglishPod, my name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today we're
talking about a very popular kind of movie.
That's right, today
we're talking about
Twilight and all the creatures
that you can find in this new movie.
Okay, so the name of
the movie is Twilight,
let's take a listen to
today's dialogue, we'll
be back in a moment to
talk about what's going on.
You want to go to the movies tonight?
Sure, what's playing?
The new Twilight movie!
Twilight?
As in the vampire movies?
No way am I watching that.
I don't understand why
everyone is so excited
about these films about
vampires, it doesn't make sense.
Of course it does, it's like a modern tale
of Romeo and Juliet, you have a couple that
is in love but can't be together
because they're so different.
Add in the fact that
immortality and superhuman
strength is really sexy
and there you have
it.
Plus the cast is hip, young people
that make the movie even more enticing.
I don't buy into that,
I think it's just a fad.
Pretty soon this will pass and everyone
will be into werewolves or zombies.
Alright, we're back so now let's
just jump into some vocab, let's
take a look at what we've chosen
for you on language takeaway.
Language takeaway?
Okay, so language takeaway
today Marco, we have
three different kinds
of creature or monster.
That's right.
Anyone knows about the movie
Twilight, it's mostly about vampires.
That's right, so
vampires are a kind of
imaginary creature that
like to suck people's blood.
Right.
They have long teeth.
That's right, so they
look like people and
they go out at night
and they drink people's
blood and they can't
stand in the sunlight
because they will die if
they're in the sunlight.
That's right.
Alright, so we have
vampires and also another
type of imaginary creature that we find
here is werewolves, we can find werewolves.
Okay, so you know the word wolf, a wolf is
an animal, but a werewolf is a man or woman
who turns into an animal
when the moon is full.
Right, so you're a man
or a woman by day,
but then at night when
there is a full moon,
you transform into a
wolf, so you are a werewolf.
And we have one other
kind of monster here,
this is a very disgusting kind
of monster called a zombie.
Alright, also very
popular in the movies, you
have zombies, so they're people
who are dead but they're still alive.
That's right, so they can't think.
All they want to do is
each other people and
they're usually very, very stupid and you
have to cut their heads off to kill them.
That's right, so zombies are also a very
popular type of creature in these movies.
So we have three
creatures, vampires,
werewolves and zombies,
but now let's move
on to some of the other
vocab that we found.
When the friend was
explaining about the movie
and how it's very cool,
she said that the cast is hip.
Okay, so something that
is hip is also very cool.
So a hip person is
someone who's really
interesting or cool or
maybe up-to-date current.
Right, very popular.
So for example, you
can also talk about a
place, a restaurant or
a club as being very hip.
That's right.
Now you can say these days,
bell-bottom pants are not hip anymore.
They were hip in the 1970.
That's right, so they're not cool, they're
not popular, they're not up-to-date.
Now moving on to the
end of that paragraph, we
see that the explanation
continued in saying
that the movie makes it even more enticing,
having a hip cast and a sexy theme.
So something that is enticing,
it makes you want it, okay?
So an enticing movie attracts people.
So I find warm apple pie very
enticing, it makes me want to eat it.
Okay, so something
that is enticing basically
makes you want to have
it or it makes you desire it.
Exactly.
All right, and our
last word for language
takeaway when the friend was kind
of skeptical and said, you know what?
I think it's just a fad.
Okay, something is a fad if it is a
passing trend, so it's not always popular.
It's only popular for a short time.
So the word is fad, F-A-D.
It sounds very similar to
fad, but it's not, it's a fad fad.
So we can say that
twilight is a fad, it's
something that's popular now, but
that might not be popular in two years.
Exactly, so it's
something that's very
popular now, but maybe
later it won't be like,
maybe for example,
Harry Potter was a fad.
Exactly.
So that's language takeaway
for today, but don't go anywhere.
We still have some great phrases
for you coming up in fluency builder.
You want to go to the movies tonight?
Sure.
What's playing?
The new Twilight movie.
Twilight?
As in the vampire movies?
No way am I watching that.
I don't understand why
everyone is so excited
about these films about
vampires, it doesn't make sense.
Of course it does.
It's like a modern tale
of Romeo and Juliet.
You have a couple
that is in love, but can't
be together because
they're so different.
Add in the fact that
immortality and superhuman
strength is really sexy,
and there you have it.
Plus the cast is hip, young people
that make the movie even more enticing.
I don't buy into that.
I think it's just a fad.
Pretty soon this will pass and everyone
will be into werewolves or zombies.
All right, we're back.
So now let's take a look
at a couple of phrases
we've picked out for
you on fluency builder.
Fluency Builder.
The first phrase that we have today is
related to this idea of going to the movies.
And so one of the characters today
said, sure, I want to go to the movies.
What's playing?
That's right.
Now this question is a key question and you
can use this whenever you want to know what
movie is currently being shown
at the theater or at the cinema.
Okay.
So what movie is playing?
There are many movies playing or
there are no good movies playing tonight.
That's right.
So movie plays at a theater.
Exactly.
So you want to know what
movie is playing, you say?
What movie is playing tonight?
All right.
So now for our next phrase.
This is actually going back
to the qualities of vampires.
One of the people in the dialogue described
vampires is having superhuman strength.
Okay.
So in this case, super means more than.
So superhuman strength is more
than what's normal for a human being.
So maybe a human can pick up a table.
But superhuman strength
means that if I have
it, maybe I can pick up a car or
something that's very unusual.
They're very, very heavy.
That's right.
So superhuman strength, we're
talking about how strong you are.
And then you can also mix it up
with other qualities of a person.
So for example, you can have
superhuman speed in very, very fast.
Superman is someone who had both
superhuman strength and superhuman speed.
That's right.
So it's a way to describe a person
having a quality that's more than normal.
But for our next
phrase, after superhuman
strength and something that's really sexy,
that person says, and there you have it.
And there you have it.
So why do you end that sentence
where and there you have it?
And there you have it means,
and that's the explanation.
Why?
Okay.
So let's think of the question.
The question is, why do people
like these vampire movies?
And the other person said,
well, vampires are sexy and
they're immortal and they
have superhuman strength.
And there you have it.
So that means, and that's why.
Okay.
So it's usually this phrase,
and there you have it.
You have to explain
something or give a couple
of ideas before you
say it before you use
it.
All right.
And the key here is that, and there you
have it comes at the end of that statement.
Always.
Well, you know, why is Jim popular?
You could say, well, he's funny.
He's smart.
He's good looking.
And there you have it.
Right.
Perfect.
So you're basically saying,
and that's the reason why.
All right.
And for our last phrase,
when we were talking
about a fad, the
person said, pretty soon,
this will pass and everyone will
be into werewolves or zombie.
So this might seem a little bit confusing.
What does it mean by everyone
will be into werewolves and zombies?
Okay.
So look at this as a phrase to be into.
I am into something.
You are into something.
This means I am interested in.
Okay.
So I could say, I am into books and
movies, Marco, what are you into?
So if I say I am into surfing
and bungee jumping,
I would say it sounds
like you're interested
in or it sounds like you like
sports and extreme sports.
So you can be not
only into activities, but
you can be into a specific
type of movies, for example.
I'm really into horror movies.
And I could say, I'm
not into horror movies.
I am into romantic comedies.
Okay.
So it's another way of
saying that you enjoy
it or you like it or you
realize some type of activity.
Exactly.
All right.
That's it for fluency builder.
Let's take another listen to today's
dialogue and we'll be right back.
You want to go to the movies tonight?
Sure.
What's playing?
The new Twilight movie.
Twilight?
As in the vampire movies?
No way am I watching that.
I don't understand why everyone is so
excited about these films about vampires.
It doesn't make sense.
Of course it does.
It's like a modern tale
of Romeo and Juliet.
You have a couple that is in love but can't
be together because they're so different.
That in the fact immortality and superhuman
strength is really sexy and there you have
it.
Plus the cast is hip.
Young people that make
the movie even more enticing.
I don't buy into that.
I think it's just a fad.
Pretty soon this will pass and everyone
will be into werewolves or zombies.
All right, we're back.
So obviously the
dialogue revolves around
Twilight and vampires but mostly it's
all about as we said something that's hip.
That's current.
That's popular now but
many times is also a fad.
That's right.
So let's think what was
a fad from the 1980s?
I think the 80s the fad was maybe
you can talk about the hairstyles.
Men and women had
those big kind of hairstyles
long in the back and
very tall in the front.
That's right.
As far as fashion fads, things that
were only popular for a short time.
We had big hair and we had bright colors
like electric pink and green and blue.
And also those t-shirts that would
change color when it was hot or cold.
No, those are really cool.
I think those should come back.
Those were super heavy.
Well now it's hip to wear 80s clothes.
So it's another fad.
Because then that's called
that you're being retro.
Yeah.
Yeah, retro means you like to
use styles from a long time ago.
So yeah, 77.
And in the movies now, the fad
before was magic and sorcerers.
You had Harry Potter.
Now it's turned to vampires.
That's right.
I wonder what the fad
will be in a couple of years.
I don't think, I don't agree with
the person in today's dialogue.
I don't think zombies will be a fad.
There was a short
period a couple of years
ago when there were
many, many zombie movies.
Yeah.
For example, resident
evil or Shawn of the dead.
Yeah.
But I wonder in the future if we're going
to be seeing movies about other things.
Yeah.
I imagine maybe not in
these, this, this creatures.
I don't know.
I guess vampires have
always been kind of sexy
because as you know,
they, they're immortal
and, and they're
looking, they're usually
very good looking and charming and that's
how they get their, the, their victims.
That's right.
But it's interesting to see.
Let us know.
We're really curious if
there are any local fads in
your country because
sometimes fads can be regional.
That's right.
So let us know what you're into.
Say, I'm into this.
Our website is EnglishPod.com.
All right.
We'll see you guys there.
Bye.
[BLANK_AUDIO]